about

Data Scientist with 1+ years of experience in Designing ML Models, ETL pipelines and Analysis. Possess PGD in Big Data Analytics from CDAC ACTS (HQ), Pune. Seeking to leverage my Mathematical knowledge, Analytics abilities, and ML models development competency in the role of Data Analytics.

contact



(+91) 8239-3838-47



rsohlot@gmail.com



Rewari, Haryana, IN



Linkedin.com/in/rsohlot rsohlot.github.io

EDUCATION

CDAC -PGD Big Data Analytics
Pune
Maharashtra
2018 – 2019

B.Tech. ECE Rajasthan Technical University Jaipur, RJ 2010 – 2014

SKILLS

Machine Learning
Reinforcement Learning, GAN
Python, Java, R
Big Data, Spark, Hive, Kafka
SQL (DBMS)
Mathematics (Statistics, Calculus)
Pytorch, TensorFlow

CERTIFICATION

Market Analysis Course (Jan 2017 – March 2017)

Machine Learning, Coursera (May 2016- June 2017)

Spark Working (Dec 2019)

GAN with Pytorch (May 2020 – June 2020)

professional experience

2019 - Present

Associate Data Scientist, KratinLLC, Nagpur

- Worked with a team of 3+ to Create an integration tool of AI and SAP to maximize the workforce utilization considering all the preferences and requirements.
- Results in saving the 500 miles every week of the workforce traveling.
- This project uses Time series prediction to estimate the future demand and optimization tool to get the best combination for the assignment.
- Tools used prophet, optaplanner, Django, plotly, pandas, docker.
- Designed and implemented the warehouse for the BI and analytics.
- It saved daily 1 hr. task of the team to fetch, validate and store the data.
- This was done with Hadoop, hive, spark, hue, Apache Atlus, Apache ranger.
- Deterministic statistics of the client's patient's successful admission.
- Results in 20% Improved admission rate after focusing more in the low conversion

2012 - 2014

Co-Founder, WHT, Bhiwadi, RJ

- Founded WHT. It was a Logistics Firm.
- Learnt the Logistics business flow of Northern India . Firm manages complete workflow of goods for the various Industries.